Experienced Multimedia Artist with a demonstrated history of working in the architecture & planning industry. Skilled in Computer Science, New Media Art, Mixed Media, Algorithmic Design, Generative Art, Movie Direction, Cinematography and Stage design. Strong arts and design professional with a Master of Architecture - MArch focused in Bionic Architecture from Pars University of Art and Architecture.

Mahziar Arjmandnia

Born in 1994, Ahwaz, Khuzestan Province, Iran. mahziar.arjmandnia@gmail.com +98 938 313 8422



LANGUAGES

- Persian (Native)
- English (Fluent)

EDUCATION

EXPERIENCES

- Shahid Chamran University
 Bachelor of Architecture (B.Arch)
 2013-2017
- Pars University of Art and Architecture
 Master of Architecture-MArch. Bionic Architecture
 2017-2020
- UNESCO Programmes: Advanced Course to Perceive Cinematography and Form in Cinema. 2021
- New Media Art Curator. "TehranXperiment" event. Flux Cultural Assosiation. Daa Theatre House. Tehran, Tehran Province, Iran. 2024
- Solo Exhibition. Untitled. Patio Sapce Gallery. Tehran, Tehran Province, Iran. 2023
- Cooperating with "FAR" Architectural Studio Design Projects. 2022-2023
- Cooperating with "Vergeur" Architectural Studio Design Projects. 2022-2023
- Group Exhibition. Towards a New Intellectual Cosmos: A Reflection on Contemporary Forms of Expressions .Daa Art. UK, London. 15 October 2022 15 January 2023
- Cooperating with "Luxury House" Architectural Studio Design Projects. 2022-2023 such as:

Working with Phase I Architectural Team, Babolsar Tower Design

- Video Art "Nafas". Selected. IMARP Festival. São Paulo, Brazil. 2021
- Online Course with Massoud Farassati: "Knowing Alfred Hitchcock". 2021
- Online Course on Python Programming Language (Advanced). 2021
- Online Course on C++ Programming Language (Basic). 2021
- Documentary Director and Cinematographer: Sahnè. 2019-2021:

Quarter-Finalist. Sama International Film Festival. Stockholm, Sweden. 2021

Selected. Lift-OFF Global Network Sessions. Buckinghamshire, UK. 2021

Selected. First-Time Filmmaker Online Session. Buckinghamshire, UK. 2021

Selected. Festival de Cinema Alter do Chao. Santarem, Brazil. 2020

Selected. FLICKFAIR. Los Angeles, California, United States of America. 2020

Selected, Best of Latin America Short Film Festival, Los Angeles, California, United States of America, 2020

- Group Exhibition. Chaos .Saye Art Gallery. Tehran, Tehran Province, Iran. 2020
- Music Track. "One of Those Days". Selected for Noise a Noise 20.3-2 (Compilation Album, Disc 2). Noise a Noise Records, 2020
- Audio Visual Improvisation with Faraz Bakhgooei (As a Part of Noise -a- Noise Label). 2020
- Book, a Selection of Artists and Carbafoo Activities, June 2018 June 2020
- Group Exhibition. The Second Annual of Selected Postal Cards by Carbafoo. Saye Art Gallery. Tehran, Tehran Province, Iran. 2020
- Group Exhibition. A Study of the Evolution of Contemporary Iranian Art.Freya/Espinas Art Gallery. Tehran, Tehran Province, Iran. 2020
- Stage Design, "Cotard" Theatre, Darbast Platform, Mohsen Art Gallery, Tehran, Tehran Province, Iran. 2019
- Solo Exhibition. Higgs Boson. Saye Art Gallery. Tehran, Tehran Province, Iran. 2019
- A Session with Shahriar Vaghfipour: Reviewing the Late Trends of Contemporary Art. 2019
- Audio Visual Improvisation with CHIKITAZ Band. 2019
- The Linear City Simulation Using Artificial intelligence and Cellular Automata Logic, by Python script. 2018
- Cooperating with "White Line" Architectural Studio Design Projects. 2017-2018, such as:

Parametric VIP Hall Design, Iran Mall, Tehran

5 Storey Apartment Facade Design, Yousef Abad, Tehran

4 Typical plan interior design, Fatemi Ave, Tehran

Squash Salon planning, Iran Mall, Tehran

- Teacher Assistant, Dr. Jahangir Darvish, "Stability and Combination of Structural and Architectural Design" Seminar. 2017
- Photographer and Cinematographer, Shahid Chamran Audio-Visual Team. 2016
- Solo Exhibition. A Natural disaster. Mehr Art Gallery. Ahwaz, Khuzestan Province, Iran. 2016
- Photographer, Dezfool Jundi Shapur « Shavadoon » Architectural Magazine. 2016
- Cover Designer, Shahid Chamran « Manshoor » Periodical Art Magzine. 2016
- Cooperation with Ahvaz Beautification Organisation in « Ahvaz beautification master plan project». 2014-2016
- Director and Cinematographer, 2 Academic Teasers. 2015
- Documentary Director: Mehregan-e-Khamoosh. 2015
- Translator, Shahid Chamran « Orchin » architectural magazine. 2015
- Solo Exhibitin. Covert. Mehr Art Gallery. Ahwaz, Khuzestan Province, Iran. 2014

RESEARCHES

- Artificial intelligence and swarm intelligence, and their relationship with architecture.
- Unity in diversity, one of the most outstanding charactristics of Islamic architecture.
- Architecture, Cinema and Visual Experiences: Reviewing the Late Trends
- Behavior Modification Strategies for Urban Places,
 Using Cultural Algorithm

S K I L L S E T

- New Media Artist
- Stage Designer
- Filmmaker
- CinematographerArt Director
- Art Critic
- Architect